<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[beautifully serialized nonsense]]></title>
  <link href="http://to-json.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://to-json.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-30T17:10:48-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://to-json.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[jason]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Followup to 'Piston Is Really Fun']]></title>
    <link href="http://to-json.github.io/blog/2014/11/30/a-followup-to-piston-is-really-fun/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-30T17:04:38-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://to-json.github.io/blog/2014/11/30/a-followup-to-piston-is-really-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So apparently I neglected to make a post to accompany the annotations I wrote
for the code in the Piston is Really Fun post. Here is a link to the repo with
the annotated code</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/to-json/piston-annotated-demo" title="piston-annotated-demo">piston-annotated-demo</a></p>

<p>I hope it turns out to be useful to someone. It was fun discovering the basics
and I look forward to coming up with something more interesting to do with
this powerful tool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wow, Piston Is Really Fun!]]></title>
    <link href="http://to-json.github.io/blog/2014/11/21/wow/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-21T22:50:08-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://to-json.github.io/blog/2014/11/21/wow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently started experimenting with game development libraries, largely
because the kids in my life have made the connection that:</p>

<ul>
<li>Games are Programs</li>
<li>I make Programs</li>
<li>-> I could make games</li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;ve tried explaining that the sort of programming I do is very boring and
practical, but they correctly recognize that nothing stops me from changing
that. So, I&rsquo;ve tried a few things in recent weeks:</p>

<ul>
<li>Quil - wonderful for art and play, but not my style for games</li>
<li>RustAllegro - Allegro is delightful and simple but this library is
a bit undermaintained at the moment, and for getting in to game dev I&rsquo;d
like something that works predictably and has batteries included</li>
<li>Rot.js - I will do something with this, but that&rsquo;s for me and my nostalgia.
It&rsquo;s tougher to get modern kids excited about UTF-8 graphics.</li>
<li>rust-sdl2 - This seemed like a great fit at first, but then I couldn&rsquo;t
figure out quickly how to interact with time. While trying to resolve that
I (re)discovered Piston</li>
</ul>


<p>When I first heard of Piston a few months back, I still felt like Rust was
gross and full of grunt work like C/C++. However, more recently I&rsquo;ve been
toying with it to see if anything might pull me into the static typing camp;
Scala and Haskell were appealing, but they didn&rsquo;t seem to offer enough of a
performance advantage over clojure to convince my lizard brain to work through
the tough parts. Go had the performance benefits, but it&rsquo;s type-checker barely
does anything! Hardly the strong advertisement for type-safety I was seeking.</p>

<p>Rust magically seems to do it all, plus it&rsquo;s still unpopular and pre-1.0 which
delights my inner hipster.</p>

<p>Piston can use rust-sdl2, but it offers much more than that. It sits on top of
a variety of rust libraries and provides an opinionated interface to them. It
is almost <em>too</em> easy to set up an event loop and get a (super) basic engine
up and running.</p>

<p>For instance, here&rsquo;s the code for a controllable square. You can compile this
and play with it, as is.</p>

<pre><code class="rust">
extern crate graphics;
extern crate input;
extern crate piston;
extern crate sdl2_window;
extern crate opengl_graphics;
extern crate shader_version;
extern crate event;

use sdl2_window::Sdl2Window;
use opengl_graphics::Gl;
use shader_version::opengl::OpenGL_3_2;

use std::cell::RefCell;
use piston::{
    RenderArgs,
    UpdateArgs
};

use input::{
    Button,
    Keyboard
};

use graphics::{
    Context,
    AddRectangle,
    AddColor,
    Draw,
};

use event::{
    Events,
    Window,
    RenderEvent,
    PressEvent,
};

pub struct App {
    gl: Gl,       // OpenGL drawing backend.
    rotation: f64, // Rotation for the square.
    player: Player
}

pub struct Player {
    x: f64,
    y: f64
}

impl App {
    fn render&lt;W: Window&gt;(&amp;mut self, _: &amp;mut W, args: &amp;RenderArgs) {
        let context = &amp;Context::abs(args.width as f64, args.height as f64);
        context.rgba(0.4,0.4,0.4,1.0).draw(&amp;mut self.gl);

        context
            .rect(self.player.x, self.player.y, 50.0, 50.0)
            .rgba(0.8, 0.0, 0.0,1.0)
            .draw(&amp;mut self.gl);
    }
}

fn handleKey(key: Button, app: &amp;mut App) {
    match key {
        Keyboard(input::keyboard::Up) =&gt; { app.player.y -= 10.0 }
        Keyboard(input::keyboard::Down) =&gt; { app.player.y += 10.0 }
        Keyboard(input::keyboard::Left) =&gt; { app.player.x -= 10.0 }
        Keyboard(input::keyboard::Right) =&gt; { app.player.x += 10.0 }
        _ =&gt; {}
    }
}

fn main() {
    let window = Sdl2Window::new(
        OpenGL_3_2,
        piston::WindowSettings::default()
    );

    let mut player = Player { x: 50.0, y: 50.0 };
    let mut app = App { gl: Gl::new(OpenGL_3_2), rotation: 0.0, player: player };

    let window = RefCell::new(window);
    for e in Events::new(&amp;window) {
        e.press(|key| handleKey(key, &amp;mut app));
        e.render(|r| app.render(window.borrow_mut().deref_mut(), r));
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>There&rsquo;s a lot going on there, and I&rsquo;ll talk about it more in another post but
there&rsquo;s kind of super simple examples out there so I wanted to get this up
out while I&rsquo;m still thinking about it. A controllable square really isn&rsquo;t
much, but it&rsquo;s an excellent starting point. You get</p>

<ul>
<li>opening a window</li>
<li>drawing to the window</li>
<li>tracking state</li>
<li>handling input</li>
<li>color</li>
<li>using library code</li>
<li>functions and methods</li>
</ul>


<p>all in 80-some lines. There are games that can be written at this point,
given a crude collision detection scheme.</p>

<p>Hopefully soon I&rsquo;ll write a walkthrough of that code.</p>

<p>For now, sleep.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Brief Introduction]]></title>
    <link href="http://to-json.github.io/blog/2014/08/10/a-brief-introduction/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-10T14:38:57-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://to-json.github.io/blog/2014/08/10/a-brief-introduction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Who the hell are you?</h1>

<p>Hi, I&rsquo;m Jason Saxon. You might know me from such who am I kidding you almost
certainly don&rsquo;t know me from anything. I&rsquo;m actually not sure how you got here,
but since you&rsquo;re here and haven&rsquo;t stopped reading yet, I assume you to be
interested in who I am.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m currently a software test engineer for a Minneapolis-based software
company called Code 42. I don&rsquo;t represent them in any meaningful capacity
publicly, but they do great work and you should check it out. Especially
if you need endpoint backup or enterprise-grade file-sharing. Or a job.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also a nerd. If there is one constant in my life, it&rsquo;s that. I&rsquo;ve been
a into a wide variety of games, from classic pen-and-paper titles to the
latest console wizardry. At any given moment I have an obsession I&rsquo;d like to
talk your ears off about (thus the blog). I like to think about programming,
technology, the future, human social structure, cultural anthropology, ethics,
comedy, music, creativity, policy, and <em>so much more</em>.</p>

<p>What you&rsquo;re likely to find here are what many would refer to as rants;
under-structured, stream-of-consciousness writing about a relatively specific
topic, with too large a helping of emotional intensity, and too liberal an
application of mental lubricants. Targets, for the time being, will probably
tend to be programming related, but who knows what the future holds.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also pretty purely self taught; I have no formal education past high
school, with the exception of a few basic courses at a local community
college. This is just short of intentional; I am incompatible with a system
that stratifies education along pre-existing lines of economic inequity; the
internet serves as a better school for my ethical framework. As a result,
alongside rants, you&rsquo;re likely to find articles that lay out my process as I
fumble my way towards understanding some concept.</p>

<p>Beyond this post, you wont find much about my personal life. I&rsquo;m not a fan
of that form of blogging, so I want to get all of that identity sharing
nonsense out of the way as quickly as possible; you probably don&rsquo;t care if
I just had a rough day at work or what my cat did last night, and even if you
did, I don&rsquo;t care to share it, at least not so publicly.</p>

<h2>I stopped reading about 5 paragraphs ago; care to summarize?</h2>

<p>This is a place to capture rants and neat things I learn, and to talk about
them at length.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
