<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Personal | beautifully serialized nonsense]]></title>
  <link href="http://to-json.github.io/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://to-json.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-30T17:10:48-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://to-json.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[jason]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Brief Introduction]]></title>
    <link href="http://to-json.github.io/blog/2014/08/10/a-brief-introduction/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-10T14:38:57-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://to-json.github.io/blog/2014/08/10/a-brief-introduction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Who the hell are you?</h1>

<p>Hi, I&rsquo;m Jason Saxon. You might know me from such who am I kidding you almost
certainly don&rsquo;t know me from anything. I&rsquo;m actually not sure how you got here,
but since you&rsquo;re here and haven&rsquo;t stopped reading yet, I assume you to be
interested in who I am.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m currently a software test engineer for a Minneapolis-based software
company called Code 42. I don&rsquo;t represent them in any meaningful capacity
publicly, but they do great work and you should check it out. Especially
if you need endpoint backup or enterprise-grade file-sharing. Or a job.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also a nerd. If there is one constant in my life, it&rsquo;s that. I&rsquo;ve been
a into a wide variety of games, from classic pen-and-paper titles to the
latest console wizardry. At any given moment I have an obsession I&rsquo;d like to
talk your ears off about (thus the blog). I like to think about programming,
technology, the future, human social structure, cultural anthropology, ethics,
comedy, music, creativity, policy, and <em>so much more</em>.</p>

<p>What you&rsquo;re likely to find here are what many would refer to as rants;
under-structured, stream-of-consciousness writing about a relatively specific
topic, with too large a helping of emotional intensity, and too liberal an
application of mental lubricants. Targets, for the time being, will probably
tend to be programming related, but who knows what the future holds.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also pretty purely self taught; I have no formal education past high
school, with the exception of a few basic courses at a local community
college. This is just short of intentional; I am incompatible with a system
that stratifies education along pre-existing lines of economic inequity; the
internet serves as a better school for my ethical framework. As a result,
alongside rants, you&rsquo;re likely to find articles that lay out my process as I
fumble my way towards understanding some concept.</p>

<p>Beyond this post, you wont find much about my personal life. I&rsquo;m not a fan
of that form of blogging, so I want to get all of that identity sharing
nonsense out of the way as quickly as possible; you probably don&rsquo;t care if
I just had a rough day at work or what my cat did last night, and even if you
did, I don&rsquo;t care to share it, at least not so publicly.</p>

<h2>I stopped reading about 5 paragraphs ago; care to summarize?</h2>

<p>This is a place to capture rants and neat things I learn, and to talk about
them at length.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
